I just don't understand why people
（紫原(むらさきばら)）やっぱり理解できないな
勝てないのに
努力する人間の気持ちは
work so hard when they can't win.
I said it doesn't matter if I win, but don't get the wrong idea.
（木吉(きよし)）勝てるかどうか
関係ないと言ったが—
勘違いするなよ
（木吉）
負けるつもりも毛頭ない！
I don't intend to lose either!
うらあ！
（紫原）だったら教えてやるよ
I'll show you just how cruel a sport basketball is.
バスケが どんだけ
残酷なスポーツかってことを
Hard work, determination, faith...
努力だの 根性だの 信念だの…
I'll crush them all.
（紫原）ひねり潰してやるよ
すべて
All of them.
shoudou ga atte usoppachi ni idonde
I've got the urge to challenge these bold-faced lies.
boku to kimi to ga shujinkou Love song
You and I are the stars of this love song.
dondon ikimashou
It's time to pick up the pace
Translation Checking: AMS
tsuyoki de semeraretanda
before I lose out to some go-getter,
nakamauchi no warai banashi de wa
and end up like the guys my friends joke about.
Editing: AMS
monmon toshitenda ze
It's starting to drive me crazy...
jibun no heya itsu datte
Always cooped up in my room.
Timing: sangofe
honto wa yowaki na peach mind
The truth is, I've got a timid peach mind
K-Timing: Eternal Blizzard
ki no aru soburi ka
Does she have a thing for me?
Typesetting: AMS, KmE
Karaoke: KmE
tada no omoikomi ka
Or am I reading too much into it?
baretenda ano ko ni wa
Either way, that girl's got us all figured out.
ganbare otoko no ko
Do your best, boys.
Encoding: Your Mom
kono mama ja sanjuugo renpai
If this keeps up, it'll be 35 straight losses.
kimi dake no boku wa Go to guy
But just for you, I'll be your go-to guy.
he
n
ge
ji
za
i
no
ma
ji
ka
ru
su
ta
a
Phantasmagoric magical star
i
da
na
ru
ma
n
ne
ri
da
t
te
i
ja
na
i
What's wrong with a tried-and-true stereotype?
to
me
ro
a
o
sa
wo
Own up to your own inexperience.
ma
da
mi
chi
nu
ko
i
na
ra
ba
If your love has yet to come full circle,
ze
n
bu
a
ge
ru
ze
I'll give you my all.
ki
mi
ni
chi
ka
u
This I swear to you.
saizen-fansubs.com
Episode
I Don't Want to Lose!
（土田(つちだ)）紫原が—
Murasakibara's on offense?
オフェンス？
I thought he only played defense.
（小金井(こがねい)）ディフェンス専門じゃ
なかったの？
Murasakibara is one of the more combative members of the Generation of Miracles.
（黒子(くろこ)）紫原君は
“キセキの世代”の中でも—
好戦的なタイプ
バスケに興味が薄く
面倒を嫌う彼は—
While he has little interest in basketball and finds it annoying,
he's actually better on offense.
本来 オフェンスのほうが
得意なくらいです
In games like this that have incurred his wrath,
特に今回のように
逆鱗(げきりん)に触れた試合では—
he's been known to score a record hundred points in a single game.
一試合で100得点という
記録も残っています
A hundred?
（土田･河原(かわはら)）100…！？
I didn't expect Murasakibara to move on his own, but
（荒木(あらき)）紫原が
自ら出たのは想定外だ…
…が
こちらにとっては うれしい誤算
it's a fortunate miscalculation on our part.
Thanks for waking the monster.
感謝するよ
怪物をわざわざ起こしてくれて
（紫原）教えてやるよ
I'll show you.
I'll show you such unfair play, it'll make your pretty words meaningless!
どんなきれい事も
身もフタもなくなるような—
理不尽を
Three?
（福井(ふくい)）３人！？
We don't expect to stop you with one.
１人で止められるなんて
思ってないさ
Really?
So what?
だから？
（水戸部(みとべ)）…っ
（日向(ひゅうが)）く！
（福井）えいっ！
どりゃああっ！
The hammer of destruction:
（荒木）破壊の鉄槌…
Thor's Hammer.
（荒木）トールハンマー
（火神(かがみ)）ああっ
（伊月(いづき)）みんな！
Guys!
Oh, sorry.
（紫原）ああ ごめーん
I didn't think you'd be knocked down so easily.
そんな簡単に散るとは
思ってなかったよ
まだだ！
We're not finished yet!
（木吉）えいっ
（伊月）ふっ
With Murasakibara on offense,
（伊月）紫原がオフェンスに
参加するということは—
we should be able to counterattack now.
カウンターが決まる隙が
できたってことだ！
We'll take back those points with fast breaks!
速攻で取り返してやる
He caught up?
（伊月）
追いつかれた… ウソだろ！？
You're kidding!
Izuki!
（木吉）伊月！！
Kiyoshi's the point guard!
木吉ポイントガード！
They stopped triple-teaming him?
（降旗(ふりはた)）
トリプルチームを解いた！？
I'll stop you myself.
（紫原）
あんたは オレ１人で止める
Come on!
来いよ
（紫原）はっ
（土田）ブロックに跳んだ！
He jumped for the block!
But Kiyoshi's true skill is his ability to make passes with his Right of Postponement!
（降旗）でも 木吉先輩の
真骨頂は このあとすぐ！
（河原）後出しの権利によるパス…
He blocked the path with his left hand?
（木吉）このコースを
左手で防いだ！？
I'm tired of that strategy.
（紫原）
もう飽きたし そのパターン
と… 止められた？
He stopped it?
木吉ポイントガードが…
Kiyoshi has been defeated as a point guard.
やぶられた…
（福井）フン！
No, you don't, Murasakibara!
（火神）
させるか！ 紫原！！
Kagami!
（小金井･土田）火神！！
Basketball is a contest of shortcomings.
（紫原）そもそもバスケなんて
欠陥競技じゃん
The hoop is three meters in the air.
（紫原）
ゴールは３メートルの宙にある
You can't call that fair.
その時点で フェアなんて
言葉はないんだよ
（３人）あ…
（紫原）結局 でかいヤツが—
The game favors the tall.
勝つようにできてる
That's the foundation of this shitty sport.
それが このクソスポーツの
根本だろ
What's so fun about that?
こんなもんの何が楽しいの？
（紫原）どんな理想も
オレにとっちゃあ—
To me, all ideals are nothing but trash.
ただのゴミだ
（観客１）
ゴール ぶっ壊しやがった
He broke the hoop?
（観客２）ウソだろ…！？
You're kidding.
That's not funny.
（日向）冗談キツいぜ…
That surprised me too.
（氷室(ひむろ)）さすがに これは
こっちも驚いたな
Honestly, I've never been more glad he's on our side.
（福井）正直—
今日ほど味方でよかったと
思ったことはねぇぜ
（木吉）ハァ… ハァ…
ハァ… ハァ…
D-Due to the broken hoop,
（審判）
ゴ… ゴール破損のため—
the game will be put on hold until it can be replaced!
試合を一時中止します
交換作業が終わるまで…
Shoei Junior High
（木吉）えいっ！
（男子１）頑張ってんな！
You're working hard.
Don't push yourself too hard.
（男子２）あんまし 無理するなよ
It's so fun I can't help it.
楽しくてしょうがないんだよ
コンプレックスでしかなかった
でかい体にも—
I used to have a complex about my huge size,
but I found something even it can do.
できることが見つかってな
それに どんなヤツが来ても—
Besides, no matter who I run into,
みんなを守れるようになりたいんだ
I want to be able to protect everyone.
（紫原）結局 そんなもん？
Is that all?
I got annoyed and gave it all I had,
but it looks like I didn't need to.
つい イラついて
本気になっちゃったけど—
必要なかったわ
Teiko
Shoei
そういやプレー中に
何か… “守る”とか言ってた？
During the game, you said something about protecting someone, didn't you?
Teiko
Shoei
You couldn't protect anything.
何も守れてないじゃん
（紫原）フンッ！
（日向）
くっ！ 再開早々 これかよ！
He's doing this right after the restart?
We can't stop Murasakibara!
Yosen
Seirin
紫原を止められねぇ！
Aren't I
（木吉）やっぱり—
ダメなのか？
good enough?
（福井）リバン！
Rebound!
No!
（木吉）いや 違う！！
It's not over yet!
まだ 終わってない！
（岡村(おかむら)･劉(リュウ)）ううっ！
Vice Claw!
（降旗）バイスクロー！！
Is this how you do it?
えーと… こう？
What?
Murasakibara used the Vice Claw?
紫原がバイスクロー！？
Impossible...
（木吉）そんな…
No way!
バカな！！
（火神）ざけんな！
（木吉）させるかぁ！！
You can't be serious!
No you don't!
（紫原）ううっ… ていっ！
I won't let it happen again!
（木吉）
繰り返すもんか もう二度と！
（紫原）うううっ えいっ！
（木吉･火神）がっ！！
Kagami!
（伊月）火神！
（日向）木吉！
Kiyoshi!
Damn it!
くそっ…
木吉先輩！？
Kiyoshi!
Teppei!
鉄平(てっぺい)！！
まだだ… まだ終わって…
It's not...
It's not over yet.
（木吉）ああ 悪い…
Thanks.
（黒子）あっ…
（紫原）これが現実でしょ？
This is reality.
なす術(すべ)なく体力も尽きた
Unable to do anything, you ran out of strength.
あんたが引っ込めば
インサイドは完全に死ぬ
If you're benched, you will die completely inside.
No matter how you struggle, Seirin will lose.
どうあがいても誠凛(せいりん)の負けだよ
How do you feel?
…で どう？
また 何も
守れなかったわけだけど…
You weren't able to protect anything again,
楽しかった？
but did you have fun playing basketball?
バスケ
Murasakibara, what do you think you're doing?
紫原 どういうつもりだ！
I just helped him up.
（紫原）起こしてあげただけだよ
（紫原）はい
（日向）うおっ… あっ 木吉！
Here.
Kiyoshi...
Seirin, member change!
（審判）誠凛 選手交代！
Kiyoshi!
木吉先輩…
すまんな
Sorry.
The rest is up to you.
あとは… 頼む
勝ってくれ
Please win.
Murasakibara, you bastard!
紫原 テメエ！
ん？ 何 怒ってんの？
What are you so mad about?
（黒子）紫原君は さっき—
You said if we benched Kiyoshi,
木吉先輩が抜けたら—
Seirin would lose, no matter how we struggled.
どうあがいても
誠凛は負けだと言いました
Yeah.
The game isn't over yet. Besides,
まだ終わってませんよ
それに…
いなくても意思は受け取っています
even if he's not on the court, his will is with us.
I will beat you in his place!
ボクが代わりに君を倒す！
オレを倒す？
Beat me?
そんなこと もし本気で
言ってるんだとしたら—
If you're being serious,
ひねり潰すよ
I'll crush you.
Even you, Kuro-chin.
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
黒(くろ)ちんでも
（帝光(ていこう)部員たち）おい…
（さつき）ちょ… どうしたの！？
Hey... What's going on?
Murasakibara's bad habit again.
（青峰(あおみね)）また 紫原の悪い癖が出た
With that player who had just been promoted from the second team yesterday.
昨日 ２軍から
上がってきたばっかのヤツに…
（男子１）うっ ハァ… ハァ…
You think you can accomplish anything using hard work with your level of skill?
（紫原）その程度の才能で—
頑張れば何とかなると
思ってんの？
Maybe you should just quit basketball.
やめたほうが
いいんじゃない… バスケ
（男子１）えっ… ハァッ
Jeez... Why does Muk always do that?
もう ムッ君は
なんでそういうことを いっつも…
Don't bother.
（緑間(みどりま)）やめておけ
（さつき）あっ…
Those who can come back will.
戻ってくるヤツは戻ってくる
人に言われて
やめてしまうぐらいなら—
If they quit just because they're told to, they wouldn't have lasted long either way.
どの道 長くは続かないのだよ
Case in point, Kuroko is still here.
事実 それでも黒子は
ここで生き残っているだろう
I like basketball and work hard to get better at it.
（黒子）バスケが好きで
うまくなるために努力する
What's wrong with that?
その何がいけないんですか？
Everything. It's pointless.
いけないよ 無意味じゃん
頑張れば
誰でも夢はかなうと思ってんの？
Do you think everyone can make their dreams come true through hard work?
努力が実るとは限らない
Hard work isn't always rewarded.
That's common sense.
そんなもん常識でしょ
（黒子）否定はできません
I can't deny that.
実際 才能や資質というものは
あると思います
I believe in skill and natural talent.
けど…
However,
that doesn't mean hard work won't be rewarded.
実らないとも限らない
Those two usually get along.
（黄瀬(きせ)）あの２人 普段は
仲悪くないんスけどねー
つーか—
Anyway, it's a good thing Akashicchi and the coaches are out.
赤司(あかし)っちとコーチたちが
ちょうど外してて助かったっスわ
いたら 超ペナルティっスよ
こういうの
If they were here, they'd punish this heavily.
Maybe they just can't help it.
こればっかりは—
しょうがねえことなのかも
しんねえな
After all, they've walked completely different paths.
なんせ ２人が歩んできた
バスケット人生は—
まったく逆だかんな
バスケにさして
興味がないにも関わらず—
Despite his lack of interest in basketball,
才能に恵まれ 勝ち続けて来た紫原
the talented Murasakibara has experienced victory after victory.
Without talent despite his love of the game,
好きでも才能に恵まれず—
絶望すら味わって
やっと活路を見つけたテツ
Tetsu experienced hopelessness before finally finding his way.
It's impossible for them to see eye-to-eye.
そんな２人に同じ価値観を
持てっつうのが無理なんだ
（黄瀬）ハァ…
Who do you think is right, Aominecchi?
で… 青峰っちは
どっちが正しいと思うんスか？
How should I know?
知るかよ
Everyone's free to have their own opinion on basketball.
バスケをどう思ってるかなんて
人それぞれだろ
There's no point in denying it.
それを否定しても意味ねえし
However, if you want to push your convictions, you have to win.
ただ それでも
自分の信念 貫きてえなら—
戦って勝つしか ねえんじゃねえの
I'll never lose to someone like you who denies the efforts of others!
人の努力を
否定してしまう君には—
絶対 負けたくない！
I keep telling you, your pretty words are so annoying, Kuro-chin.
だから—
そういうきれい事が
ウザいっつってんだよ
黒ちんさぁ！
（木吉）頼むぞ… 黒子
Please, Kuroko.
I'll stop you!
（劉）止める！
（紫原）くうっ！
He's closing in faster than the last half.
前半より つめてくるのが早い！
This is...
これは…
Atsushi, if he tries that disappearing shot again, don't try to block it like you normally would.
（氷室）敦(あつし) もし消える
シュートが来たら—
ブロックは はたくな
His shot appears to disappear, but the ball doesn't disappear.
彼のシュートは
消えたように見えるが—
ボールがなくなるわけじゃない
Even if you can't see it, the ball is following a flight path like a normal shot.
見えなくても
通常のシュートと同じように—
放物線に飛んでいる
When blocking his shots,
だから… ブロックのときは—
keep your arm out between him and the hoop.
リングと彼の間に
手を伸ばし続ければいい
（紫原）うっ この高さで
ボールに触れない！？
I can't touch the ball at this height?
あっ 敦！
違う これは…
Atsushi, no!
パスだ！
It's a pass!
（火神）えい！
I can't break it after all.
さすがに ぶっ壊すのは無理か
Bastard...
このっ…
All right!
よっしゃあ！
ハァ…
みんなで力を合わせて—
You're all about working together, aren't you?
結局 そういうことでしょ いつも
But I told you.
けど 言ったろ
Everything is trash before me.
オレの前じゃ 全部ゴミだって
Of course we're working together.
みんなで戦うのは
もちろんそのつもりです
…が 言ったはずです
However, I told you.
Murasakibara,
紫原君 君を倒すと
I will beat you.
（さつき）
テツ君がムッ君をマーク！？
Tetsu's on Muk?
If you keep playing around, you'll get hurt, Kuro-chin.
あのさぁ…
ふざけてるとケガするよ？ 黒ちん
I'm not playing around.
ふざけていません
I'm going to stop you, Murasakibara.
止める気ですから 紫原君を
This is...
（紫原）これは…
（紫原）ええぃ…
（紫原）軽う〜
He's so light.
You're so light, I can't even tell you're there.
軽すぎているかいないか
分かんなくなるんだけど？
綿あめかい！
What are you made of, cotton candy?
そんなヤツ いないも同然だ！
If he's going to be on him, it's only natural!
決めちまえ 敦！
Make the shot, Atsushi!
（紫原）えっ… いない
どこ行った？
He's not there?
Where did he go?
あっ 敦！
Atsushi!
Charging, white No. 9!
（審判）チャージング！
白 ９番
Seirin ball!
誠凛ボール！！
なるほどな
I see.
Are you okay?
大丈夫かよ おい
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
He used his lack of power and presence to make him think he wasn't even there, and then moved into his path.
（青峰）非力さと
影の薄さを利用して—
いないも同然と意識させ—
不用意に動いたところへ現れる
Basketball's not so simple that you can win just by being big, Murasakibara.
大きいだけで勝てるほど
バスケは単純じゃないですよ
紫原君
やってくれんじゃん！
You've done it now.
Nice work, Kuroko.
（日向）よくやった 黒子！
When you said you'd take on Murasakibara alone,
（伊月）１人で紫原に付くって
言い出したときは—
耳を疑ったけど
その手があったか！
I couldn't believe it, but that worked.
I won't be able to use that strategy anymore.
けど この方法は もう使えません
だから このあとは…
After this,
あのディフェンス
フォーメーションを—
let's use that defensive formation.
やらせてください
Yosen
Seirin
（岡村）えーい
（日向）フゥ…
Barrier Jumper?
（岡村）バリアジャンパー！？
Is he pulling that out now?
まさか このタイミングで！？
（岡村）ええーい
（日向）えいっ
A quick three-pointer?
（劉）いきなりスリーポイント！？
Kiyoshi's not on the inside anymore.
（福井）もう中に木吉はいない
If he misses, a counterattack is guaranteed.
外せば カウンターは確実…
What?! There's no way I'll miss!
（日向）
あぁ！？ 外すわけねぇだろが！
Kuroko's not the only one.
黒子だけじゃねぇ
I want to throw a wrench in your plans too!
一泡 吹かせてやりたいのは
オレもなんだよ！
何！？
What?
Let's go!
行くぞ！！ 新フォーメーション！
New formation!
（さつき）オールコート
マンツーマンディフェンス！？
Full court man-to-man defense?
（氷室）そう きたか
This is their strategy.
If they let Atsushi get the ball, they won't be able to stop him.
ひとたび敦に
ボールを持たせれば止める術はない
By setting up their defense before Murasakibara gets under the basket,
（岡村）紫原がゴール下に
たどり着く前に仕掛けて—
強引にスタミナと走力勝負に
持ち込んできおった！！
they're forcing a battle of stamina and speed.
In order to break through, we'll just use our speed too!
（福井）突破するには—
こっちも走力だ！
走れ！ 動きを止めたら
一気に捕まるぞ！
Run!
If you stop moving, they'll jump on you!
（岡村）おっ ちょっと待て？
Hold on.
敦！
Atsushi!
How long has he been marking me?
（岡村）こいつ いつの間に
ワシのマークに！？
It's not a standard full-court man-to-man defense.
（氷室）ただの
オールコートマンツーマンじゃない
細かくマークチェンジを
繰り返してる！
They're switching their marks continuously.
We told you.
（リコ）言ったでしょ
新フォーメーションだって
It's a new formation.
This formation gives Kuroko the highest chance of stealing.
これは… 黒子君のスティールを
最大限に活かす—
ステルス･オールコート
マンツーマンディフェンス
It's the Stealth Full-Court Man-to-Man Defense.
（小金井）うぉぉぉぉ！
（土田）黒子ぉぉぉ！！
Kuroko!
Yosen
Seirin
Breaking through a full-court defense requires speed and passing,
（氷室）オールコート系
ディフェンスを突破するには—
走力とパス回しが重要だが—
but with Kuroko frequently changing his mark,
黒子君が頻繁にマークチェンジして
神出鬼没—
we can't throw careless passes!
うかつにパスが回せない
If we can't pass...
（福井）パスがダメなら…
What?
Did he let me by on purpose because he knew Kuroko was there?
（福井）こいつ
黒子がいるのを分かってて—
わざと抜かせやがった
Seirin
Yosen
All right!
（降旗）やったぁー！！
（福田）伊月先輩！
Izuki!
No basket!
（審判）ノーカウント
（火神）ドンマイっス
（伊月）あぁ…
Don't worry about it.
Yeah.
（審判）２分間 休憩に入ります
We will now take a two minute break.
フゥ…
イテえ…
Ow!
物に当たってんじゃねぇよ！
Don't take your anger out on objects!
The fourth quarter will start with us inbounding the ball.
第４クォーターは
ウチボールからスローインだ
自動的にハーフコートから
開始できるから—
The game will restart automatically with us inbounding it from half-court, so we have to make this shot.
ここを確実に決めること
After that, if we move carelessly against their full-court man-to-man, it's easy to lose sight of Kuroko.
そのあとの
オールコートマンツーは—
なまじ動けば
黒子を見失いやすくなるし—
If we pass, the risk of the ball being stolen increases.
パスを回せば
カットされるリスクが上がる
Consequently, we have only one option for breaking through.
よって 突破方法は一択
Himuro will dribble the ball through.
氷室のドリブルで突き破る
Yosen's ace isn't just Murasakibara.
陽泉(ようせん)のエースは紫原ではない
Murasakibara and Himuro are our aces.
紫原と氷室のダブルエースだ
Running a full-court defense is rough.
（伊月）やはりキツいな
オールコートは…
Can we last until the end of the game?
最後まで持つか？
持たすんだよ
We'll make it last.
But I can't imagine that Yosen won't try anything.
けど—
このまま陽泉が
何もしてこないとは考えられないわ
（火神）カントク それなんスけど
（リコ）ん？
Coach, about that.
Once they break through our full-court defense and move to a half-court game,
オールコートで突破されて
ハーフコートに移行したとき—
２(ツー)-３(スリー)ゾーンで 真ん中を
オレにやらせてくれ… です
let's run a 2-3 zone with me in the middle.
What?
The same formation as Yosen?
陽泉と同じフォーメーションで！？
Like Murasakibara, I'll cover the entire two point area.
オレが紫原と同じように—
ツーポイントエリア全域を
カバーする
できんのか そんなこと！？
You can do that?
誰が来ようとオレが止める！
No matter who comes, I'll stop them.
For Kiyoshi.
木吉先輩の分まで！
（木吉）火神…
Kagami...
分かったわ
Got it.
In the fourth quarter, we'll run the Stealth Man-to-Man Full-Court and a 2-3 zone half-court...
第４クォーターは…
オールコートは—
ステルス･オールコート
マンツーマンディフェンス
ハーフコートは
２-３ゾーンで…
木吉！ 何ボーっとしてんだよ！
Kiyoshi, why are you just sitting there?
オマエもいいアイディアあったら…
なっ！？
If you have any good ideas...
What?
なんで泣いてんだ オマエ！？
Why are you crying?
Teppei?
（リコ）鉄平！？
Oh, this is...
ん？ あっ これは… なんでだ？
Why am I crying?
That's what I'd like to know!
って こっちが
聞いてんだろうが！！
（木吉）あ… いや…
I don't know how to put it, but it's probably...
うまく言えないけど… たぶん…
You guys seem so reliable. I'm relieved.
オマエら見てたら
頼もしくてホッとしたっていうか…
１人じゃないことを実感して—
When I realized I wasn't alone, I couldn't help myself.
つい… な
What? Why are you stating the obvious now?
はあ？ いまさら何 当たり前のこと
言ってんだ オマエ！！
（日向）逆に腹立つわ！
（木吉）え？
I'm actually kind of pissed!
What?
Sorry. Honestly, I'm angry too.
（火神）すんません 正直オレも…
（黒子）ボクも…
Me too.
Koga, could you get my beating stick out of my bag?
（伊月）コガ ちょっと
そこのバッグからハリセン出して
Huh? Did you really put—
（小金井）え？ そんなの
あっ… あった！？
You did?!
Hey, this isn't the time for that!
ちょっと 今
それどころじゃないでしょ！！
Oh,
そうか
I get it.
A team isn't just something to be protected.
チームってのは—
守るだけのもんじゃねぇんだな
守ってくれるのも—
A team also protects you.
チーム…
チームがあって—
We don't support each other because we're a team.
一人一人が支えてる
わけじゃなく—
We're a team because we support each other.
一人一人が支えあって
初めてできるもの
それがチーム
I won't waver again.
だから もう二度と揺るがない
I...
オレは やっぱり…
（黒子）あの…
Why don't we form a circle again?
もう一度 円陣 組みませんか？
紫原君が言った
バスケは不公平だというのは—
In some ways, I think Murasakibara was right when he said basketball isn't fair.
ある種 真実だと思います
けど…
However,
バスケは１人でやるものじゃない
basketball isn't a game you play alone.
みんなで戦って勝ちたいし—
I want to win together, and I believe we can do it.
できると信じてます
Okay, then.
うっし じゃあ…
Let's go!
行くぞ！
Seirin, fight!
誠凛 ファイ！
Yeah!
（紫原）何か みんなで
仲良く気合入れてたみたいだけど…
It looks like you were hyping each other up, but...
I'm going to crush everything.
ひねり潰すよ そんなもん全部
そんなヤワじゃないですよ 誠凛は
Seirin's not that weak.
I won't hold back.
手加減しねーぜ！
当然だ 決着をつけるぞ
Of course. Let's settle this.
Let's go!
いくぞ！
Let's win this game!
絶対 勝つ！！
リコ
Riko, I really do think basketball is fun.
やっぱりオレはバスケが楽しい
I'm glad I play.
やっててよかったよ
えっ… 何言ってんのよ 急に…？
Where did that come from?
So I'm sorry.
（木吉）だから すまん…
This is the last time.
もう これっきりだ
頼みがある
I need a favor.
kasunda mirai wo kirisaku you ni terasu hikari
Like a shining light that cuts through the hazy future,
musuu no kanousei wo motome
I chase after unlimited possibilities.
Gotta open my eyes
Wake up sabitsuita me ni hi wo tomose
Wake up, light a fire in your tired eyes.
Get up kusubutteru baai ja nainda zettai
Get up! Now's definitely not the time to let it smoulder.
youi sareta risou nante iranai
You don't need to have some big dream.
yuragu koto no nai ishi to
Just an unwavering spirit,
mikansei na chizu de ii kara
and an unfinished map is enough.
asu wo tsukame kono te de
Hold on to tomorrow with these hands!
detarame na rizumu de nurikaete iku kako ni
Regretting a past that's being overwritten by a nonsensical rhythm...
koukai hitotsu arienai daro
That's not possible, right?
ari no mama no biito de kurikaeshite iku genzei wo
I'll rewrite things with the true beat now,
kasaneta mirai kagayaku you ni
and create a sparkling future.
kizami konda sonzai wo kesshou toshite
Your existence is etched as a crystal.
Keep it in my story
Next Episode
Seirin benched Kiyoshi?
（笠松(かさまつ)）
誠凛 木吉は下げたのか？
Seirin
Yosen
They're hanging on, but it's rough.
Seirin
Yosen
食らいついちゃいるが 厳しいな
Seirin
Yosen
What are you doing, Kagamicchi?
（黄瀬）
ったく… 何やってんスか 火神っち
What's he panicking for?
（笠松）
あいつ 何 焦ってんだ？
He's not panicking. He's trying to rely on the Zone.
（黄瀬）焦ってんじゃなくて
すがってんスよ ゾーンに
Episode
Enough